Jonathan Collins

New York, United States



jonathan.collins@live.com



linkedin.com/in/jonmcollins



available upon request



https://jcodes.page

Summary

Skills | Summary

Self taught Full Stack Developer 4+ years experience working with JavaScript, React, Gatsby, NodeJS, MongoDB, Firestore, Shopify ECommerce, Jamstack, Strapi, Version Control, Software Development Life Cycle methods, and more. I've built various applications on typically small teams focused on feature development, user experiences, and custom API creation. I also extensively use and integrate third party API's into existing stacks for data retrieval and presentation. I am a dedicated problem solver and life long learner. I possess a CSM/ PSM certificate from Scrum.org on agile development practices and I am pursuing certification as a CSD/PSD. I am currently learning Java and Next.js. I shifted from an established career in finance to pursue my passion for programming and development of web applications.

Experience



W Web Developer

Lineage Logistics

May 2020 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

In my current role I work to develop applications that provide data solutions for a vast team that includes a wide range of specializations from transportation to finance. I work with both frontend and backend technologies, primarily based in JavaScript such as React and Node. I am asked to evaluate third party software solutions for possible

integration into existing stacks, frameworks, and environments. I work on a small development team that integrates with functional IT personnel to provide easy to use development solutions to the less technical working groups within the company. I conceptualize and build projects using JavaScript, JSON, and often integrate with complex logistical databases and third party API's centered around inventory materials and product order detail.



Vistex Engineer and Web Developer

Maines Paper and Food Service, Inc.

Nov 2014 - May 2020 (5 years 7 months)

Built income tracking programs within the Vistex bolt-on

component of SAP - responsible for billing and tracking over 15

million in ARR. Developed the company's initial Truck Tracking program using a complex Verizon API and JavaScript web interface to track, and

notify, stakeholders on delivery/late delivery metrics. Conceptualized and built a JavaScript/JSON web interface for Product Line Managers to enter contract details to be tracked via the SAP Vistex Module. The application also had a complex workflow component with staged progress notification to involved users.

Broker

HSBC

Aug 2004 - Nov 2014 (10 years 4 months)

Managed client wealth portfolios and helped to diversify wealth

holdings and vehicles. Built customized portfolio analytics programs to gain better insight around client mismatches of tolerance vs instrument holdings.



Sep 1995 - Jul 1999 (3 years 11 months)

Education



Whitney Point High School

Diploma, Liberal Arts and Sciences, General Studies and Humanities 1994 - 1999 Regents Diploma

Licenses & Certifications



Certified ScrumMaster (CSM) - Scrum.org

517ccf0d-c666-4f77-a20e-5581b8d8bec5

Skills

JavaScript • React.js • GatsbyJS • MongoDB • Mongoose ODM • Node.js • Scrum • JAMstack · Strapi.js · Version Control

Honors & Awards



MVP of the Year - Maines Paper and Food Service, Inc.

Jan 2015

Received most valuable person award for creating a blueprinting program that allowed for the onboarding of multi-million dollar logistics contract for a nationally recognized chain.